<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The XAPI Toolstack on XAPI Toolstack Developer Documentation</title><link>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/index.html</link><description>Recent content in The XAPI Toolstack on XAPI Toolstack Developer Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Responsibilities</title><link>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/responsibilities/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/responsibilities/index.html</guid><description>The XAPI Toolstack forms the main control plane of a pool of XenServer hosts. It allow the administrator to:
Configure the hardware resources of XenServer hosts: storage, networking, graphics, memory. Create, configure and destroy VMs and their virtual resources. Control the lifecycle of VMs. Monitor the status of hosts, VMs and related resources. To this, the Toolstack:
Exposes an API that can be accessed by external clients over HTTP(s). Exposes a CLI.</description></item><item><title>High-level architecture</title><link>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/high-level/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/high-level/index.html</guid><description>The XAPI Toolstack manages a cluster of hosts, network switches and storage on behalf of clients such as XenCenter and Xen Orchestra.
The most fundamental concept is of a Resource pool: the whole cluster managed as a single entity. The following diagram shows a cluster of hosts running xapi, all sharing some storage:
At any time, at most one host is known as the pool coordinator (formerly known as &amp;ldquo;master&amp;rdquo;) and is responsible for coordination and locking resources within the pool.</description></item></channel></rss>