<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>High-level architecture on XAPI Toolstack Developer Documentation</title><link>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/high-level/index.html</link><description>Recent content in High-level architecture on XAPI Toolstack Developer Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/high-level/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Environment</title><link>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/high-level/environment/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/high-level/environment/index.html</guid><description>The Toolstack runs in an environment on a server (host) that has:
Physical hardware. The Xen hypervisor. The control domain (domain 0): the priviledged domain that the Toolstack runs in. Other, mostly unpriviledged domains, usually for guests (VMs). The Toolstack relies on various bits of software inside the control domain, and directly communicates with most of these:
Linux kernel including drivers for hardware and Xen paravirtualised devices (e.g. netback and blkback).</description></item><item><title>Daemons</title><link>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/high-level/daemons/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/high-level/daemons/index.html</guid><description>The Toolstack consists of a set of co-operating daemons:
xapi manages clusters of hosts, co-ordinating access to shared storage and networking. xenopsd a low-level &amp;ldquo;domain manager&amp;rdquo; which takes care of creating, suspending, resuming, migrating, rebooting domains by interacting with Xen via libxc and libxl. xcp-rrdd a performance counter monitoring daemon which aggregates &amp;ldquo;datasources&amp;rdquo; defined via a plugin API and records history for each. There are various rrdd-plugin daemons: xcp-rrdd-gpumon xcp-rrdd-iostat xcp-rrdd-squeezed xcp-rrdd-xenpm xcp-networkd a host network manager which takes care of configuring interfaces, bridges and OpenVSwitch instances squeezed a daemon in charge of VM memory management xapi-storage-script for storage manipulation over SMAPIv3 message-switch exchanges messages between the daemons on a host v6d controls which features are enabled.</description></item><item><title>Interfaces</title><link>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/high-level/interfaces/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://robhoes.github.io/xen-api/new-docs/toolstack/high-level/interfaces/index.html</guid><description>Communication between the Toolstack daemon is built upon libraries from a component called xapi-idl.
Abstracts communication between daemons over the message-switch using JSON/RPC. Contains the definition of the interfaces exposed by the daemons (except xapi).</description></item></channel></rss>