<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Squeezed :: XAPI Toolstack Developer Documentation</title><link>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/squeezed/index.html</link><description>Squeezed is the XAPI Toolstack’s host memory manager (aka balloon driver). Squeezed uses ballooning to move memory between running VMs, to avoid wasting host memory.
Principles Avoid wasting host memory: unused memory should be put to use by returning it to VMs. Memory should be shared in proportion to the configured policy. Operate entirely at the level of domains (not VMs), and be independent of Xen toolstack.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/squeezed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Architecture</title><link>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/squeezed/architecture/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/squeezed/architecture/index.html</guid><description>Squeezed is responsible for managing the memory on a single host. Squeezed “balances” memory between VMs according to a policy written to Xenstore.
The following diagram shows the internals of Squeezed:
At the center of squeezed is an abstract model of a Xen host. The model includes:
The amount of already-used host memory (used by fixed overheads such as Xen and the crash kernel). Per-domain memory policy specifically dynamic-min and dynamic-max which together describe a range, within which the domain’s actual used memory should remain.</description></item><item><title>Design</title><link>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/squeezed/design/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/squeezed/design/index.html</guid><description>Squeezed is a single host memory ballooning daemon. It helps by:
Allowing VM memory to be adjusted dynamically without having to reboot; and Avoiding wasting memory by keeping everything fully utilised, while retaining the ability to take memory back to start new VMs. Squeezed currently includes a simple Ballooning policy which serves as a useful default. The policy is written with respect to an abstract Xen memory model, which is based on a number of assumptions about the environment, for example that most domains have co-operative balloon drivers.</description></item><item><title>Overview of the memory squeezer</title><link>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/squeezed/squeezer/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/squeezed/squeezer/index.html</guid><description>Warning This was converted to markdown from squeezer.tex. It is not clear how much of this document is still relevant and/or already present in the other docs.
summary ballooning is a per-domain operation; not a per-VM operation. A VM may be represented by multiple domains (currently localhost migrate, in the future stubdomains)
most free host memory is divided up between running domains proportionally, so they all end up with the same value of ratio</description></item></channel></rss>