<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design :: XAPI Toolstack Developer Documentation</title><link>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/index.html</link><description/><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Events</title><link>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/Events/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/Events/index.html</guid><description>ids rather than data; inherently coalescable blocking poll + async operations implies a client needs 2 connections coarse granularity similarity and differences with: XenAPI, event channels, xenstore watches https://github.com/xapi-project/xen-api/blob/30cc9a72e8726d1e7501cd01ddb27ced6d53b9be/ocaml/xapi/xapi_xenops.ml#L1467</description></item><item><title>Hooks</title><link>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/hooks/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/hooks/index.html</guid><description>There are a number of hook points at which xenopsd may execute certain scripts. These scripts are found in hook-specific directories of the form /etc/xapi.d/&lt;hookname>/. All executable scripts in these directories are run with the following arguments:
&lt;script.sh> -reason &lt;reason> -vmuuid &lt;uuid of VM> The scripts are executed in filename-order. By convention, the filenames are usually of the form 10resetvdis.
The hook points are:
vm-pre-shutdown vm-pre-migrate vm-post-migrate (Dundee only) vm-pre-start vm-pre-reboot vm-pre-resume vm-post-resume (Dundee only) vm-post-destroy and the reason codes are:</description></item><item><title>PVS Proxy OVS Rules</title><link>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/pvs-proxy-ovs/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/pvs-proxy-ovs/index.html</guid><description>Rule Design The Open vSwitch (OVS) daemon implements a programmable switch. XenServer uses it to re-direct traffic between three entities:
PVS server - identified by its IP address a local VM - identified by its MAC address a local Proxy - identified by its MAC address VM and PVS server are unaware of the Proxy; xapi configures OVS to redirect traffic between PVS and VM to pass through the proxy.</description></item><item><title>Requirements for suspend image framing</title><link>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/suspend-image-considerations/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/suspend-image-considerations/index.html</guid><description>We are currently (Dec 2013) undergoing a transition from the ‘classic’ xenopsd backend (built upon calls to libxc) to the ‘xenlight’ backend built on top of the officially supported libxl API.
During this work, we have come across an incompatibility between the suspend images created using the ‘classic’ backend and those created using the new libxl-based backend. This needed to be fixed to enable RPU to any new version of XenServer.</description></item><item><title>Suspend image framing format</title><link>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/suspend-image-framing-format/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/suspend-image-framing-format/index.html</guid><description>Example suspend image layout:
+----------------------------+ | 1. Suspend image signature | +============================+ | 2.0 Xenops header | | 2.1 Xenops record | +============================+ | 3.0 Libxc header | | 3.1 Libxc record | +============================+ | 4.0 Qemu header | | 4.1 Qemu save record | +============================+ | 5.0 End_of_image footer | +----------------------------+ A suspend image is now constructed as a series of header-record pairs. The initial signature (1.) is used to determine whether we are dealing with the unstructured, “legacy” suspend image or the new, structured format.</description></item><item><title>Tasks</title><link>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/Tasks/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xapi-project.github.io/new-docs/xenopsd/design/Tasks/index.html</guid><description>Some operations performed by Xenopsd are blocking, for example:
suspend/resume/migration attaching disks (where the SMAPI VDI.attach/activate calls can perform network I/O) We want to be able to
present the user with an idea of progress (perhaps via a “progress bar”) allow the user to cancel a blocked operation that is taking too long associate logging with the user/client-initiated actions that spawned them Principles all operations which may block (the vast majority) should be written in an asynchronous style i.</description></item></channel></rss>